Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
Isabelle...
（ルツ）
イザベル…
I'm getting used to my new life.
俺は新しい暮らしに
慣れてきたところだ
How about you?
お前は どうだ？
Are you sleeping well?
穏やかに眠れているか？
That's dangerous, Ruth.
ルツ 危ないよ
S-Sorry. I was so happy, I couldn't stop myself.
（ルツ）すっ すまない
楽しくて つい…
Welcome home, Ruth.
おかえり ルツ
I'm home, Chise.
（ルツ）ただいま チセ
Silver.
銀の君…
How's Elias?
エリアスは？
今日もか…
Still?
Elias...
（チセ）エリアス？
朝食が出来たみたいなんですが…
It seems like breakfast is ready.
（エリアス）ああ ごめんね
Sorry.
“今日も食事はいい”って
銀の君に伝えてくれるかい？
Can you tell Silver that I don't need to eat today, either?
I wonder what's wrong with him.
（チセ）どうしたんだろうね
教会から帰ってきて ２週間も
部屋から出てこないなんて…
It's been two weeks since we got back from the
church, and he still hasn't come out of his room.
Why don't you open the door and ask?
（ルツ）
ドアを開けて
本人に聞けばいいだろ？
Let's go, Ruth.
（チセ）行こう ルツ
（ルツ）ハア…
Maybe the transformation
from the fight took a toll on him.
（ルツ）
戦ったとき変化したのが
体に こたえたのかもしれないな
（チセ）変化？
Transformation?
It takes a lot of energy to
change your appearance, maybe?
（ルツ）
姿が変わるのは力を使う… のか？
Why do you say that like a question?
（チセ）なんで疑問形なの？
I can't quite remember.
（ルツ）うまく思い出せないんだ
Maybe it hasn't quite hit me that I'm a fairy.
まだ 妖精なんて言われて
ピンときてないせいかもな
（チセ）ふ〜ん…
Are you settled in now?
ルツは落ち着いた？
You've been exploring the property this whole time.
ずっと敷地を探検してたけど
It's something I need to do.
（ルツ）
あれは必要なんだよ　本能的に
Instinctively.
As a dog?
（チセ）犬的に？
I don't want to admit it, but yeah.
（ルツ）認めたくないけど そう
（チセ）これ なあに？
What's this?
え？ ちょっ… シルキー？
W-Wait, Silky.
What is it, Chise?
（ルツ）どうした？ チセ
I-I don't know what just
happened, but we got kicked out.
よっ よく分からないうちに
放り出されたんだけど…
"For a change of pace.
“気分転換”
Be back before it gets dark."
“暗くなる前に 帰ってくること”
It looks like she gave us some spending money.
お小遣いをくれたみたいだね
Looks like it.
（ルツ）みたいだな
I wonder if it's safe to go out right now, though.
（チセ）
だけど 大丈夫かな？
今 外に出たりして
You have me.
（ルツ）俺がいるだろ
Hey, long time no see, Chise!
（アンジェリカ）
おや 久しぶりだね チセ
Angelica-san.
（チセ）アンジェリカさん
How've you been?
元気にしてたかい？
（ヒューゴ）よお！ 愛し仔(ロビン)
Hey, Robin.
Um...
（チセ）あの…
（アンジェリカ）ん？
Elias is a bit...
（チセ）エリアスは ちょっと今…
No, I'm not asking about him.
いや あいつは関係ないよ
I want to know how you're doing.
あんたが どうしてるかと思ってさ
Do you have some time?
ちょっと時間あるかい？
（アンジェリカ）買ったねえ！
Talk about a shopping spree.
I can't buy any gifts for Silky, but I'm
hoping there's something she can use at home.
（チセ）
シルキーに
お土産… は渡せないんですけど
何か うちで使えるものが
あればって
That sounds good.
（アンジェリカ）そりゃあ いいね
Now, can I take a look?
さて… ちょいと見せてくれ
It looks like it's functioning properly.
問題なく機能してるみたいだ
体の調子は？
How do you feel?
Nothing unusual.
（チセ）いえ 特には…
She looks sleepy all the time.
（ルツ）いつも眠そうにしている
ルツ！
Ruth!
You seem especially tired after you use magic.
（ルツ）
魔法を使ったあとは
特に だるそうだ
ぐお〜！
Learn to depend on people,
or you'll screw something up...
遠慮ばかりしてると 踏み外すよ
いつか１人で立ったときにね
When you're on your own someday.
あんたがチセの使い魔だね
ありがとう
You must be Chise's familiar.
Thank you.
（ルツ）お前は いいヤツそうだ
You seem like a good person.
Don't try to do everything by yourself.
何でも１人でやろうとしないこと
Otherwise, what's the point of having helpful neighbors?
何のために
力を貸してくれる隣人がいるのさ
You're hot-blooded, but you have a weak heart.
あんたは血の気が
とっても多いけど
心臓が弱い
You have to take care of your body.
だから
自分の体を いたわらなきゃね
I'll do my best.
（チセ）努力… してみます
Speaking of which, what are you doing about school?
（アンジェリカ）
そういえば あんた 学校は？
You could be going to school, at your age.
あんたぐらいの年なら
まだ学校に通うのも
手じゃないのかい？
I don't know.
（チセ）学校は…
I have to take care of the flowers and herbs.
花やハーブの世話もあるし
魔法の勉強は大変だけど
Studying magic is a lot of work.
Each season has its own special
chores to do and lessons for me to learn.
夏には夏の 冬には冬の
仕事や勉強があって
I'm just content being allowed
to stay with Elias and the others.
エリアスたちがいる家に
置いてもらえるだけで…
それで十分です
（アンジェリカ）チセ
Chise, are you sure you aren't being overly dependent?
それは依存じゃないのかい？
You're young.
あんたは若い
You have a long time ahead of you.
これから長いんだよ
Don't spend your time relying on handouts from others.
与えられるものだけ食べてたら
ダメだ
You were bought by Ainsworth.
あんたは
エインズワースに買われた子だ
I know you had a hard time elsewhere,
よそで
あまりいい思いをしなかったのも
少しは知っている
but you don't have to be fixed to him.
だけど
あいつだけを見てる必要はないんだ
I-I'm sorry.
す… すいません！
I didn't mean that.
こんなこと やるつもりじゃ…
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい！
いや… 私も言い過ぎたよ
No, I've said too much.
（チセ）違うんです…
That's not true.
I know you're right.
分かってはいるんです
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
（アンジェリカ）フウ…
（アンジェリカ）
悪かったね 今日は
Sorry about today.
No, thank you for caring about me.
（チセ）いえ…
心配してくれて
ありがとうございます
Don't be too much of a good girl.
あんまり
いい子でいるんじゃないよ
See you, Robin, newbie.
（ヒューゴ）
じゃあな！ ロビン 新入り
I'm a coward.
（チセ）
私は… ズルい
I'm depending on someone
who doesn't think anything of me.
私のこと 何とも思ってないヒトに
寄りかかって
I tell myself that I wouldn't mind
being abandoned, yet I don't want to be.
捨てられてもかまわないって
考えながら
捨てられたくないとも思ってる
I'm selfish.
私は… 自分勝手だ
I used to hate coming home when the lights were on.
（チセ）昔は
明かりがついた家に
帰るのは苦手だったな
Chise.
（ルツ）チセ
Yes, Ruth?
（チセ）何？ ルツ
I share a little bit of many things with you.
（ルツ）俺は
お前と いろんなものを
少しずつ共有してる
Yeah.
Senses, emotions, and even memories.
（ルツ）
感覚も 感情も…
記憶だって そうだ
If that event was a curse put
upon you, I want it to be lifted soon.
あの出来事が
お前にかけられた
呪いなら
俺は それが
早く解ければいいと
思ってる
Yeah.
（チセ）
うん… ありがとう
Thanks.
（ドアが閉まる音）
（チセ）ただいま
I'm home.
Thanks for the money.
お小遣い ありがとう
I bought some gifts—I mean,
some snacks and such for us.
これは お土産… じゃなくて
私たちのお茶菓子とか
エリアスは？
How's Elias?
Elias,
（チセ）
エリアス？ 大丈夫ですか？
are you all right?
Elias, where are you?
エリアス？
どこですか？
エリ…
Eli—
（ルツ）チセ！
Chise!
Chise, sorry.
（エリアス）チセ ごめん
I can't control my body very well.
体が うまく抑えられなくて…
It might be scary, but let me stay this way.
怖いかもしれないけど
できれば このまま いさせて
Will you explain things to me in the morning?
（チセ）朝になったら…
説明してくれますか？
Yeah.
（エリアス）うん… 大丈夫
Don't worry.
An inhuman body.
（チセ）
人間じゃない体
手足
Limbs,
顔… 首…
face,
neck.
The reason I'm not scared must be
怖くないのは 多分…
because I'm cursed.
私が呪われてるからだ
（チセの母）あなたなんか…
I shouldn't have given birth to you.
産まなきゃよかった！
ハア… ハア…
エリアス？
Elias...
Elias?
エリアス？
Morning, Silky.
（チセ）おはよう シルキー
Have you seen Elias?
エリアスを知らない？
Okay.
そっか
Ruth, it's time for breakfast.
ルツ！ 朝ご飯だよ
Thanks, Silky.
ありがとう シルキー
Chise-kun.
チセ君！ よく来たね
Good to see you here.
Are you feeling better now?
もう体は大丈夫かい？
Yes, thank you.
（チセ）はい おかげさまで
（ルツ）
寄るな　お前は うさんくさい
Stay away.
You seem fake.
Ruth, why did you shrink?
ルツ どうして縮んだの？
このほうが
チセと一緒に動きやすい
I can move with you easier in this form.
I see.
（サイモン）
なるほど… 君は使い魔か
You must be her familiar.
You have a good big brother now.
いいおにいさんができたね
Stare...
あの… エリアスを知りませんか？
Um, have you seen Elias?
エインズワース？
Ainsworth?
Sorry, I don't—
う〜ん 悪いけど 知らな…
Thank you.
（チセ）ありがとうございました〜
（サイモン）て… 早っ！ 早い！
Wait, so soon?
君！ ちょっと
あいつに似てきたんじゃない？
I think he's rubbing off on you!
Where is he?
（チセ）ホント どこにいるかな
（ルツ）
チセはエリアスを愛してるんだな
You must really love him.
なっ… なんで？
Wh-Why?
You're afraid of him being gone.
（ルツ）
あいつがいないのを恐れてる
More than that, you're worried.
でも それよりも心配してる
But...
（チセ）でも…
Why do you try to deny it?
なぜ否定しようとするんだ？
It's important to love something other than yourself.
自分以外の何かを愛するのは
大事なことだ
It's important both to protect that
something, as well as for your own sake.
何かを守るために…
自分自身のためにも大切なことだ
俺はチセを愛してるし
イザベルも ずっと愛する
I love you, and I'll always love Isabelle.
それじゃあ いけないのか？
Is that wrong?
I wish it were that easy.
簡単に そう思えたら
いいんだけどね
You're so obstinate.
チセは強情だ
Well, hello.
（ジョエル）おや こんにちは
Hello.
こんにち… は…
（ジョエル）見ない顔だね
I haven't seen you before.
We just moved here recently.
つい最近 近くに越してきたので
Is that so?
そうかい そうかい
It's remote, but it's nice here, isn't it?
田舎だが ここは いい場所だろう？
Feel free to come see my garden, if you're interested.
うちの庭が気に入ったなら
気軽に見ていってくれ
The queens will be happy, too.
そのほうが
美人さんたちも喜ぶだろう
Hey, you're a Sleigh Beggy.
あんた 夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)じゃないの！
珍しい！
That's unusual!
私のこと 口に出したら
食べちゃうからね
Speak of me, and I'll eat you.
リャナン･シー
A Leannán Sídhe.
She's a vampire that grants a
man talent in exchange for his blood.
男の血と引き換えに才能を与える
吸血鬼だ
（リャナン･シー）
そういう あんたは… ワンコロね
Meanwhile, you're just a doggy.
Aren't your kind interested in younger men?
（ルツ）
お前らの好みは
もっと若い男のはずだろ
Suck that man's blood, and he'll die in an instant.
あんなヤツから血を吸ったら
すぐに死ぬ…
（リャナン･シー）
あんたが あの影の茨(ソーン)の嫁なのね
So, you're Thorn's bride.
弟子です
Apprentice.
Hey!
ちょっと！
Would you two like to come in for tea?
（ジョエル）
２人とも お茶でも どうだい？
Go get some rest, Chise.
（ルツ）チセは少し休んでいけ
You look pale from your lack of sleep.
お前 寝不足で 顔色悪いぞ
（ルツ）見つけたら呼ぶ
（チセ）えっ… ルツ！
I'll let you know if I find him.
Ruth.
手を出したら引き裂くぞ 吸血鬼
Mess with her, and I'll rip you apart, vampire.
（リャナン･シー）ウフフ
I live alone here, so I've been longing for someone to have some tea with me.
（ジョエル）僕は独り身でね
そろそろ お茶の相手が恋しいと
思っていたところだったんだ
I'm Joel Garland.
僕はジョエル･ガーランド
What about you?
お嬢さんは？
（チセ）チセ･ハトリです
Chise Hatori.
That's an amazing book collection.
すごい本ですね
（ジョエル）好きでね
I like books.
I write my own, occasionally.
時折 自分でも書いてみるが
なかなかに楽しい
It's quite enjoyable.
I have a short story, actually. Could I ask you to read it?
もしよかったら 短編があるから
読んでみてくれないかい？
Um, uh, but...
（チセ）えっと…
あの でも…
Do you not have time?
もしかして 時間がないかい？
I'm not good at reading.
（チセ）
読むのは不得意なので
時間がかかるかもしれませんが…
It might take a long time.
かまわないさ！
That's all right.
It was a love story.
（チセ）
恋の話だった
バラの庭で出会った２人の
A simple story about two
people who meet in a rose garden.
何てことない
けれど どこか懐かしいような…
But there was something nostalgic about it.
（リャナン･シー）
いいお話だったでしょ？
Wasn't it a nice story?
Yes, but it didn't seem like
you were giving him the talent.
でも… 別に あなたが
才能あげてるわけじゃないような
気がしたけど
どうして 彼に憑(つ)いてるの？
Why are you haunting him?
You're not taking his blood, either.
血も吸ってなさそうだし…
I felt like our eyes met that day, in the rose garden.
目が… 合った気がしたの
あの日 バラの庭で
It's not like he's my type!
好みじゃなかったのよ？
He's old, and a skinny slob to boot!
ジジイだし ズボラだし
痩せっぽちで！
He doesn't have anything he's
devoting his life to or anything, either,
何かに命を懸けてるほど
のめり込んでるものもない
so I can't take his blood.
だから 血を飲めない
And I can't give him what I otherwise could.
あげるものも あげられない
I don't know what to do.
どうしていいか分からない…
Maybe, since you're a human, you understand how I feel.
人間のあんただったら
この変な気持ちが分かるかしら？
Sorry. I can't believe I dozed off.
（ジョエル）
すまないね 居眠りなんて
I've been really sleepy lately.
最近 とても眠くて
Was that story about the roses here?
（チセ）
もしかして あの小説は
ここのバラが題材だったり？
アハハ！ バレたか
You got me.
I once saw someone very beautiful here, a long time ago.
昔 ここで
とても美しい人を見たんだよ
It might have been a daydream, but it must have been...
白昼夢だったかもしれないが
あれは きっと…
ジョエルさん？
Joel-san?
Oh, it's nothing.
いや… 何でもないよ
I feel like our eyes met again just now.
さっきね
また 目が合った気がしたわ
Was it because of you?
あんたのせいかしら
Are you in lo—
あなたは ジョエルさんのことが…
That's not the answer I'm looking for.
それは
私の欲しい答えじゃない
私たちの愛し方は
食べて与えること
We love by consuming and giving.
So I don't love him.
だから 私は
あれを愛してはいない
Come give him a visit again.
また来てあげて
It'll make him happy.
ジョエルが喜ぶから
Uh, okay.
（チセ）あ… はい
It's not a word that I deserve to say
when all I can think about is myself.
（チセ）
自分のことしか
考えられないような私が
言える言葉じゃないよね
（ルツ）
チセ
Chise.
（チセ）あ… ルツ！
Ruth.
（ルツ）
あいつを見つけた
I found him.
He's in the forests north of the house.
家の北にある森の奥だ
ハア… ハア…
Over there.
（ルツ）あそこに
（エリアス）チセ…
Chise.
It's dangerous to come into the forest at dusk.
黄昏時(たそがれどき)に森に入るのは危ないよ
I left you a note saying I'd be home by night.
夜には戻るって メモに…
あなたは…
You aren't going to tell me anything, are you?
何も話してくれないんですね
Why this is happening, what kind of creature you are...
どうして
こんなことになってるのか
自分が どんな生き物なのかも
You always avoid me when I ask.
ほかのことだって
いつも ごまかして…
You're always quick to understand.
（エリアス）
だって
君は物分かりがいいじゃないか
You accepted what I said without questioning me.
僕の言葉を
そのまま受け取ってくれていただろ
だからって！
That doesn't mean...
No matter how selfish I am,
いくら私が自分勝手でも
何も知らずにいられるほど
it's not like I'm so disinterested in you
that I can bear not knowing about you.
私は
あなたに興味ないわけじゃない
I've never seen you make such a face.
（エリアス）そんな顔 初めて見た
Was I making a weird face?
（チセ）
何か 変な顔をしてましたか？
Yes, I've never seen you like that.
（エリアス）うん 見覚えない
Were you looking for me the whole time?
ずっと 僕を捜してたの？
メモを残しておいたのに
I left you a note and everything.
Huh?
えっ！ なに？
すごい顔だよ？
What?
You're making a scary face.
Are you asking me to just take that note
and leave you, with the way things were going?
あの成り行きで
あのメモで放っておけと？
いくら私が鵜呑(うの)みにするからって
I may accept everything you say,
but if you vanish on me like that...
いきなり いなくなられたら…
ハア…
Why were you resting here?
どうして
こんな所で休んでるんですか？
（エリアス）
体のバランスが崩れたんだ
My body's out of balance.
I was here adjusting.
それで ここで調整をしてた
ここまで 何とか…
Half of what he says is a lie.
（チセ）
本当と うそが入り混じってる…
多分
I think.
I didn't mind him trying to gloss things over before.
前までは
ごまかされてもかまわなかったのに
Why am I so scared now?
どうして 今は
こんなに怖いんだろう
As for any other questions you may have
about me, could you give me a little time?
（エリアス）
僕についての そのほかは
少し待ってくれるかな
I want time to gather my thoughts.
ちょっとだけ
整理する時間が欲しい
I'll be waiting, then.
じゃあ… 待ってます
（ルツ）フン…
Are you angry?
（エリアス）怒ってる？
I'm not angry.
（チセ）
怒ってないですよ… 怒っては
Not angry.
What are you thinking about, then?
（エリアス）
じゃあ 何を考えてるの？
（チセ）だから 別に どうも…
（落下音）
I told you, I'm not...
（セルキー）ズドボッシャーン！
Kaboosh!
Elias!
（チセ）エ… エリアス！
（チセ）えっ… 妖精？
（セルキー）よいしょ…
A fairy?
Echos' familiar.
（エリアス）白花の歌(エコーズ)の使い魔？
（チセ）えっ…
"From Lindenbaum to Thorn."
I have a message from Lindel-sama.
リンデンバウムから
ソーンへ！
リンデル様から
伝言なのですよ
"I have business with the
child you foster. Come quickly..."
〝養い子に要件あり
至急 来られたし〞
"To the land of dragons."
〝ドラゴンの国へ！〞
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
（チセ）
再び ドラゴンの国を訪れた少女
The girl visits the land of dragons for a second time.
There, she learns of a side to the
mage that she'd never known before.
そこで語られたのは
彼女の知らない魔法使いの姿だった
It came as certain as the night.
（リンデル）
それは 夜が二つ足で歩むがごとく
やって来た